export const Questions = [
    {
        questionh: "एक रूमाल के चार कोने हैं। उनमें से अगर दो कोनों को काट दिया जाए तो कितने कोने बचेंगे ?",
        question: "A handkerchief has four corners. If two corners are cut off, how many corners will be left?",
        optionA: "4",
        optionB: "8",
        optionC: "6",
        optionD: "10",
        answer: "c",
    },
    {
        questionh: "पेड़ पर पाँच पंछी बैठे थे, दो ने उड़ने का फैसला किया,बताओ कितने बचे ?",
        question: "Five birds were sitting on the tree, two decided to fly, tell how many are left?",
        optionA: "2",
        optionB: "3",
        optionC: "0",
        optionD: "5",
        answer: "d",
    },
    {
        questionh: "रमेश एक होटल का नौकर था,जो अक्सर ग्राहकोँ द्वारा सिगरेट पीने के बाद बचे 6 टुकड़ो को जोड़ कर एक पूरी सिगरेट बनाकर पी जाता था। एक दिन उसे 216 टुकड़े मिल गये तो बताईये उस दिन रमेश ने कितनी सिगरेट पी?",
        question: "Ramesh was a hotel servant, who often used to make a complete cigarette by joining the 6 pieces left after the customers smoked. One day he got 216 pieces, so how many cigarettes did Ramesh smoke that day?",
        optionA: "43",
        optionB: "42",
        optionC: "36",
        optionD: "44",
        answer: "a",
    },
    {
        questionh: "एक दुकान वाला एक चॉकलेट 1 रुपये में देता है और आप चॉकलेट के 3 खाली पैकेट देकर 1 चॉकलेट मुफ्त ले सकते हैं।अगर आपके पास 15 रुपये हैं तो आप कितने चॉकलेट खा सकते हैं?",
        question: "A shopkeeper gives a chocolate for 1 rupee and you can get 1 chocolate free by giving 3 empty packets of chocolate. How much chocolate can you eat if you have Rs 15?",
        optionA: "21",
        optionB: "20",
        optionC: "15",
        optionD: "22",
        answer: "a",
    },
    {
        questionh: "एक तालाब में एक अजीब कमल का फूल खिल रहा है।जो हर रोज पहले से दुगना हो जाता है।जैसे अगर आज 1 इंच है तो कल 2 इंच हो जायेगा।परसो 4 इंच हो जाएगा।अगर इस तरह से हिसाब लगाया जाये,तो ये फूल 30 दिन में पूरा तालाब भर देगा।तो बताइए ये फूल आधे तालाब को कितने अरसे में भरेगा?",
        question: "A strange lotus flower is blooming in a pond. Which is doubled every day. For example, if it is 1 inch today, it will be 2 inches tomorrow. The day after tomorrow it will be 4 inches. If calculated in this way, then this flower will fill the entire pond in 30 days. So tell me, in how much time will this flower fill half the pond?",
        optionA: "15",
        optionB: "29",
        optionC: "30",
        optionD: "1",
        answer: "b",
    },
    {
        questionh: "अगर  8 को आधा कर दिया जाए तो  0 और  4 के अलावा और क्या जवाब आएगा  ?",
        question: "If 8 is halved, what will be the answer other than 0 and 4?",
        optionA: "4",
        optionB: "0",
        optionC: "3",
        optionD: "1/2",
        answer: "c",
    },
    {
        questionh: "दो हवाई जहाज़ हैं। एक 600 कि.मी. प्रति घंटा की रफ़्तार से दिल्ली से लंदन जा रहा है और दूसरा 500 कि.मी. प्रति घंटा की रफ़्तार से लंदन से दिल्ली जा रहा है।जब वो मिलेंगे तो कौन सा जहाज़ लंदन के करीब होगा?",
        question: "There are two aeroplanes. A 600 kms.  per hour going from Delhi to London and the other at 500 kms.  is going from London to Delhi at an hourly speed. Which ship will be closer to London when they meet?",
        optionA: "Incomplete Question",
        optionB: "Second Aeroplane",
        optionC: "First Aeroplane",
        optionD: "Both",
        answer: "d",
    },
    {
        questionh: "मान लीजिए आप बस में 10 सवारियों के साथ सफर कर रहे हैं। पहले स्टैंड में 2 सवारी उत्तरी और 4 चढ़ीं। दूसरे स्टैंड में 5 उतरी और 2 चढ़ीं। अगले स्टैंड में 2 उतरी और 3 चढ़ीं।अब बताओ बस मेंकितनी सवारियां सफर कर रही है।",
        question: "Suppose you are traveling with 10 passengers in a bus. At the first stand 2 ride alight and 4 board. At the second stand 5 alight and 2 board. At the next stand 2 alight and 3 board. Now tell how many passengers are traveling in the bus Is.",
        optionA: "11",
        optionB: "10",
        optionC: "12",
        optionD: "9",
        answer: "a",
    },
    {
        questionh: "सुरेश एक शिकारी था ।उसका खासियत थी कि वो एक गोली से 10 सांप मार सकता था। पेङ में 100 सांप लटके थे ।सुरेश ने गोली मारी 10 सांप मर कर गिर गये तो बताइये पेड़ पर कितने सांप बच गये?",
        question: "Suresh was a hunter. His specialty was that he could kill 10 snakes with a single shot. There were 100 snakes hanging in the tree. Suresh shot 10 snakes and fell dead, then tell how many snakes survived on the tree?",
        optionA: "90",
        optionB: "0",
        optionC: "99",
        optionD: "100",
        answer: "a",
    },
    {
        questionh: "मैं मॉल जा रहा था। मैं सात पत्नियों के साथ एक आदमी से मिला।प्रत्येक पत्नी ने दो बैग रखे थे। प्रत्येक बैग में एक बिल्ली थी। प्रत्येक बिल्ली के छह बच्चे थे।तो मॉल कितने लोग जा रहे हैं?",
        question: "I was going to the mall. I met a man with seven wives. Each wife carried two bags. There was a cat in each bag. Each cat had six kittens. So how many people are going to the mall?",
        optionA: "106",
        optionB: "105",
        optionC: "3",
        optionD: "1",
        answer: "d",
    },
    {
        questionh: "दो भालुओं कि 40 मीटर उंचाई वाले स्थान में भंयकर लड़ाई हो रही थी। दोनो गुत्थम-गुत्था हुए हवा में होकर 10 मीटर प्रति सेकण्ड के गुरूत्वाकर्षण बल से धरती पर गिर गये। एक भालू मर गया। एक बच गया। बताइये मरे और बचे भालू का रंग क्या था?",
        question: "There was a fierce fight between the two bears at a height of 40 meters. Both got tangled in the air and fell on the earth with the force of gravity of 10 meters per second. A bear died. One survived. What was the color of the dead and the surviving bear?",
        optionA: "Incomplete Question",
        optionB: "Black",
        optionC: "White",
        optionD: "Brown",
        answer: "c",
    },
    {
        questionh: "10 मीटर के एक थान से एक मीटर कपड़ा का टुकड़ा काटने में 5 मिनट लगते हैं तो पूरे थान यानी 10 मीटर के 10 टुकड़े करने में कितने मिनट लगेगें?",
        question: "If it takes 5 minutes to cut a piece of cloth of one meter from a piece of 10 meter, then how many minutes will it take to cut the whole piece into 10 pieces of 10 meter?",
        optionA: "50",
        optionB: "45",
        optionC: "5",
        optionD: "60",
        answer: "b",
    },
    {
        questionh: "यदि कोई चिकित्सक आपको तीन गोलियां देता है, और हर आधे घंटे में 1 गोली खाने के लिए कहता है,तो बताओं कि,वो तीनों गोलियाँ खाने में आपको कितना समय लेगागा ?",
        question: "If a doctor gives you three pills, and asks you to eat one pill every half an hour, how long will it take you to eat all three pills?",
        optionA: "1.5 Hr",
        optionB: "1 Hr",
        optionC: "1/2 Hr",
        optionD: "2 Hr",
        answer: "b",
    },
    {
        questionh: "अगर एक क्रिकेट मैच में 10 गेंद पर लगातार 10 खिलाडी आउट हो गए तो कौन से नंबर का खिलाड़ी नाबाद रहेगा?",
        question: "If 10 players are out consecutively in 10 balls in a cricket match, then which number player will remain unbeaten?",
        optionA: "8",
        optionB: "7",
        optionC: "6",
        optionD: "11",
        answer: "a",
    },
    {
        questionh: "नदी की ओर जाते हुए एक खरगोश ने 6 हाथियो को देखा। हर एक हाथी ने भी 2 बंदरों को नदी की ओर जाते हुए देखा। हर एक बन्दर हाथ में एक एक तोता रखे हुये थे। तो अब बताइये नदी की तरफ कूल कितने जानवर जा रहे थे?",
        question: "While going towards the river, a rabbit saw 6 elephants. Each elephant also saw 2 monkeys going towards the river. Each monkey was holding a parrot in his hand. Now tell how many animals went towards the river. were you",
        optionA: "5",
        optionB: "1",
        optionC: "11",
        optionD: "0",
        answer: "a",
    },
    {
        questionh: "6 आदमी 6 आम 6 मिनट में  खाते है तो बताइये 60 आदमी 60 आम कितने मिनट में खायेगें?",
        question: "If 6 men eat 6 mangoes in 6 minutes, then tell me, in how many minutes will 60 men eat 60 mangoes?",
        optionA: "6",
        optionB: "60",
        optionC: "1",
        optionD: "0",
        answer: "a",
    },
    {
        questionh: "एक 10 लीटर का गैलन मे कुछ जीवाणु डाले गये जिनका गुण है की वो प्रतिदिन अपनी संख्या का दूना हो जाते हैं। यदि गैलन 10 दिन मे जीवाणु से पूरा 10 लीटर भर गया तो बताइये कि गैलन 5 लीटर कितने दिन मे भरा था?",
        question: "Some bacteria were put in a 10 liter gallon, whose quality is that they double their number every day. If the gallon was filled with bacteria in 10 days, then tell in how many days the gallon was filled with 5 liters?",
        optionA: "5",
        optionB: "9",
        optionC: "10",
        optionD: "6",
        answer: "b",
    },
    {
        questionh: "3 मुर्गियां 3 दिन में,3 अंडे देती हैंतो 300 मुर्गियां 300 दिन में,कितने अंडे देगी?",
        question: "If 3 hens lay 3 eggs in 3 days, how many eggs will 300 hens lay in 300 days?",
        optionA: "3",
        optionB: "300",
        optionC: "90,000",
        optionD: "30,000",
        answer: "d",
    },
    {
        questionh: "आपने एक रेस में भाग लिया और आपने दूसरे नंबर वाले रेसर को पीछे छोड़ दिया बताओ आप किस नंबर पर पहुँच गए",
        question: "You participated in a race and you left behind the second number racer, tell me what number did you reach?",
        optionA: "1",
        optionB: "2",
        optionC: "3",
        optionD: "4",
        answer: "b",
    },
    {
        questionh: "एक केला 1 रूपये का है ।ऑफर यह है कि 3 छिलके पर 1 केला फ्री। आपके पास 21 रूपये है ।आप कितने केले खा पायेंगे ?",
        question: "One banana is Re 1. The offer is that on 3 peels, 1 banana is free. You have 21 rupees. How many bananas can you eat?",
        optionA: "28",
        optionB: "21",
        optionC: "30",
        optionD: "31",
        answer: "d",
    },

]